

# Jesse Bartola

## Profile

High-achieving software engineer with over a decade of full-stack programming experience in languages such as Javascript, Typescript, Java, Python, and Scala. I take pride in tackling the most complex problems I can get my hands on. There's never a dull moment when I'm not continuously learning something new to improve myself or the world around me.

# Employment History

## Technical Lead at HubSpot, Cambridge, MA

April 2021 — Present

Technical Lead of the Automation Triggers frontend team. Lead a team of 3 engineers in redefining the way workflows are triggered using event-based data. Thought leader and main contributor to the FlowDoctor project, giving customers precise insight into the historical causes and prevention of object workflow enrollments.

Previously, was Tech Lead for the Integrations Experience and App Lifecycle FE teams.

## Senior Software Engineer I at HubSpot, Cambridge, MA

June 2020 — April 2021

Senior Software Engineer Integration Experience team. The DRI for creating a Marketing Event CRM Object, allowing customers to track and analyze events associated with Zoom, Eventbrite, GoToWebinar, and custom integrations. Responsible for cross-team collaboration in creating a front-end component framework to standardize the experience of settings pages for HubSpot-built integrations.

## Software Engineer at HubSpot, Cambridge, MA

July 2019 — June 2020

Front-end software engineer on the Integration Experience team. Responsible for creating and managing third-party app integrations within the HubSpot services platform. Addressed customer pain points by contributing to the implementation of integration sync errors solutions. Pioneered a front-end testing initiative that increased test coverage by over 100%.

## Education

B.S., Computer Science & Mathematics, University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, MA

September 2015 — May 2019

Magna Cum Laude

3.94 GPA (Overall)

4.0 Major GPA (CS & Math)

#### **Details**

Cambridge, MA United States 862-485-4641 jrbartola@gmail.com

#### Links

My Website LinkedIn GitHub

#### **Skills**

React

Javascript

**Typescript** 

Java

Python

Scala

#### **Hobbies**

Biking, chess, learning languages, reading, investing